Kyle Davis

Full Stack Web Developer

Personal Info

Address 1501 36th Ave SE Norman, OK 73026 Website stellarwebtech.com

Phone (405) 413-0606

LinkedIn /in/kyleldavis

E-mail kyledaviswx@gmail.com

Skills

JS/jQuery/ES6

PHP

MySQL/MSSQL/NOSQL

HTML/Twig

CSS

Drupal 7/8/9/10

Graphic Design/UI

AWS

Git

Adobe Creative Cloud

Composer

Docker

Full stack web developer with 15 years of experience. From database to front end and UI, I am proficient in all areas of web development and design. I have worked on multiple Drupal projects using docker, npm, composer, as well as the Pantheon platform. I have built scale-able and automated architectures that simplified the develop ment workflow. When building websites, I prioritize accessibility. My main goal is to make sure the websites and applications are reliable, accessible to all, easy to use, efficient. In 2022, I became an instructor for an online full-stack coding bootcamp. This was a wonderful and challenging experience that I am thankful for. I was able to update my knowledge on web development with some of the newest languages and tech stacks like React and the MERN stack. I love to get outside of my comfort zone and learn new things. I am alsways up for a challenge! Along with my development skills, I bring a positive energy to any team and love to work with people.

Experience

04/2018 - Present Web Development Team Lead University of Oklahoma Libraries

- Team lead for the web development team.
- Member of the web steering committee.
- Migration of a large, high-traffic site (libraries.ou.edu) from Drupal 7 to Drupal 10.
- Manage and maintain multiple websites within the libraries system.
- Completed migration of exhibits.libraries.ou.edu from Drupal 7 to Drupal 10 while switching to the Pantheon platform and reworking the theme for Bootstrap 5.
- Responsible for the Pantheon platform that is hosting all of the new sites. Created documentation and implemented the composer-based workflow needed for managing custom modules and libraries.

08/2022 - 02/2023 Instructor edX Full Stack Coding Bootcamp

- Part time instructor for a remote only full-stack coding bootcamp through the University of Minnesota and edX.
- Extensively instructed full web stack including: html, css, js, API's, sql, Node.js, Express.js, mongodb, PWA's, React, and MERN stack.
- During the course, I was able to really advance my knowledge on modern languages and tech stacks.

05/2015 - 04/2018 Web Developer Mesonet/Okla Climatological Survey

- Created and completed the Mesonet's first Drupal site for the U.S.D.A Agricultural Research Service ARS (ars.mesonet.org)
- Complete re-work of the Mesonet OKFIRE website. This fire danger management site was severely outdated and very complex. I was able to simply hundreds of pages down to a manageable list of tools. Simplicity, efficiency, and reliability were imperative to the redesign due to the nature of this life-saving project. Site: mesonet.org/index.php/okfire
- Created SVG weather widgets that retrieve live weather data and display it dynamically in the National Weather Center.

Education

2009 - The University Of Oklahoma

- Bachelor's of Science in Meteorology
- Minor in Broadcast Meteorology with Journalism and Mass Communication.
- Minor in Mathematics

Certifications

AWS Systems Operations Project Management

Conferences

05-2024 DrupalCon Portland
06-2023 DrupalCon Pittsburgh
04-2022 DrupalCon Portland
05-2020 DrupalCon Minneapolis (remote)
04-2018 DrupalCon Nashville
09-2017 ThunderPlains OKC
04-2017 DrupalCon Baltimore
05-2016 Signal by Twilio

02/2016 - 12/2019 Full Application/Web Developer PoolQueue

- Sole developer for billiards gaming start-up, "PoolQueue".
- Designed and created graphics, MYSQL database, HTML, JS, CSS, and an AWS hosted EC2 development environment as well as a load balanced production environment.
- Website provides ability to digitize a billiard hall's pool tables and digitize the wait list for the tables. New players are notified by text or voice call when the table is ready via Twilio API. Once checked in, the system charges their account and relays the confirmation to a sim card connected Arduino board in the table. The table then releases the pool balls for the players to play a game. This removes the need for tables to take change.
- Engineered and programmed the Arduino board to mechanically open and close the pool ball release pin.
- Extensive work in AWS services like S3, EC2, Route 53, RDS, and Elastic Beanstalk.

03/2013 - 04/2015 Web Developer Redibids

- · Created cutting-edge, live auction and gaming website.
- Had a significant role in developing the MSSQL database structure, database implementation, javascript/JQuery, and the site UI.
- Implemented web socket technology for the ultra-fast delivery of data. Speed was an imperative aspect of the nature of the site to deliver accurate results for users bidding on auctions.
- Created very detailed custom administration portal for the management of the site, items, and auctions.

05/2009 - 02/2013 Media Manager and Developer Weather Decision Technologies (now DTN)

- Developed weather map creator and administrative tool. Used by news stations across the US for creating customized weather maps.
- Worked as a developer for iMap, an interactive weather map with multiple layers. Used Google and MapBox maps along with custom data generated by WDT.
- Created a tool for storm chasers in our chaser network to live stream their video. The storm chaser location and live video was then shown on iMap allowing users to view multiple videos at once as weather events took place.
- Worked with application team to assist in developing and releasing over 20 iOS and Android white label apps as well as the very popular radar app, Radarscope.

2009 - 2012 iOS Application Creator/Developer Personal iOS App

- Was sole developer and owner of application.
- Application was very popular and was frequently at the top of the charts in that category. Had over 60,000 downloads for the 2 years it was on the store.